Carlos Daniel **Jiménez M.**

Colombia

🛮 (+57) 322-816-9956 | 🗷 danieljimenez88m@gmail.com | 🏕 www.danieljimemezm.com | 🖸 carlosjimenez88M | 🛅 djimenezm

Summary_

Experienced Senior Data Scientist with a demonstrated history of working in the Startups and public institutions between USA, Colombia, Chile and México. With more than ten years of experience applying and development Machine Learning models to real world.

Appasionate for applied statistics, machine learning modeling and bayesian statistics and skilled in: Applied Machine Learning, Statistical Modeling, NLP, Deep Learning, Bayesian Data Analysis, Marketing Analytics, Bio-statistics (Genomic Data analysis), LaTeX and Markdown.

You can find my Portfolio clicking here

Work Experience

Inter-American Development Bank

USA - Col

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST CONSULTANT

Jul 2020 - Currently

- · Developing Machine Learning applications to understand the public policies of the different governments
- · Deep Learning developer for NLP products
- · Developer various Machine Learning models for tasks like text classification and forecast labor in LatinAmerica

Resolve Studio - Chiper

Bogotá-Col

CHIEF DATA SCIENCE AND DATA ENGINEERING

Jan 2019- May 2020

- · Lead Data Scientist and Machine Learning developer for autonomous attributions campaings with Deep Learnning and another technologies
- Developed Data Science models solutions for classification and Data Analysis
- · Lead Data Science Team for automate solutions and tasks throughout the company such as client sales prediction, demand forecast

Big Bang Data Medellín - Col

PRE SALES ENGINEER AND DATA SCIENTIST

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2019

- · lead sales of products based on data and machine learning
- Developed Machine Learning models for: Marketing, Pricing, forecast, and Churn with differents clients
- Evaluated and Creator of work methodology

Secretaria de Educación Distrital

Bogotá - Col

Aug 2017 - Aug 2018 DATA SCIENTIST

- Data Scientist on an advanced analytics team working in education projects and innovations in big data tools (RStudio and Hadoop)
- Build and own complex data pipelines using SQL and other data processing tools
- I Created sampling model for Evaluated Educational Progress

Superintendencia de Puertos y Transporte

STATITICIAN AND QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

2017

- Created BI and tools that identify opportunities and some risk for projects
- · Worked with other departments to use new technologies to streamline Government policies and rules
- Developed a Mac and Windows python application for Policies evaluation software to measure employee productivity.

Puedo ser Consulting Group

Bogotá - Col

CHIEF STATISTICS

MARKETING' CHIEF

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

- I developed of Statistics Models to: Clusters, Marketing Analytics and Forecast
- I created Statistics department

New Port Negocios Internacionales

Bogotá - Col

NEW PORT INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

March 2014 - Apr 2015

- Researched on strategies to optimize pickup planning in warehouses
- Support Data Science initiatives across the company
- · Research the applications of AI in Marketing

Invershop SAS Bogotá - Col

• Researched on technologies to create scalable multi-tenant software Marketing

Marc 2012- March 2014

- Developing of intelligent reporting for supporting the Marketing management team
- Creation and development of Machine Learning algorithms for Marketing Strategies

DANIEL JIMÉNEZ · RÉSUMÉ SEPTEMBER 17, 2020

ONU - Secretaria de Desarrollo Económico 'La Pintana'

Chile

ASSOCIATE ECONOMIST 2012

- · I Researched and analyze labor market conditions, national and MSA patterns, and past and future market trends and forecasts
- I created Psychology Test for Social development
- I Worked with media to customize Growth Destiny's data and insights for their stories/inquiries

Academic Experience _____

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Bogotá, Coi

Professor

Dic 2019 - Currently

- Manager and creator program's on Data Science and Big Data
- Visiting professor at health school: Evaluation of medical alternatives
- Last courses(click on the course 'name to see the content)
 - Git and Github
 - Digital Data Science
 - Big Data
 - Machine Learning (Introduction)
 - Bayesian Data Analysis

Uniempresarial Boqotá, Co

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR

March 2018 - Occasionally

- Courses Creator on Data Sciene, Bl, Computational Science and Econometrics for Business
- Academic Consultat on Metacognition
- Teacher subjects on university levels :Big Data, Computational Science, Statistics and Data Analysis

Educación Futuro Bogotá- Col

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR May 2015- Apr 2016

- · Teacher at the chair of Statistics and KPI's
- Courses Creator on law of the unemployed: Innovation Diploma and Business Computing

UniAsturias Spain-México

ECONOMICS PROFESSOR 201.

• Full professor in following subjects: Microeconomics, Political Theory, Asian Economics, Economics History and Mathematical Economics

Education

Santo Tomás University

Bogotá - Col

M.S. in Statistics Jan 2018 - Currently

• focus in: Bayesian Statistics, EDA and Machine Learning Applied

Santo Tomás University

Bogotá - Col

B.A IN ECONOMICS Jan 2010 - Dec 2014

• Focus in : Maths for Economics

Tools_

Programming: Python: +4, R: +9, Octave:+3, Matlab:+2

Data Science: Tidymodels, keras, Tenserflow, Scikit Learn, tidyverse, Spark, Bigquery, MySQL, Tidymetrics

Development: Docker, Git, Google Cloud Platform, Plumber, Flask.

Visualization: Shiny, looker, Power BI, Shiny metrics, Google Analytics

Areas of Interest_

Applied Machine Learning, Natural Lenguage Processing, Statistical modelling, Econometrics (with Big Data), Genomic Data Analysis, Meta-Analysis, Bayesian data analysis, Web Scrapping, Forecasting and Deep Learning.



Inferencia estadística un enfoque moderno

www.danieljimenezm.com

TREE 2020

• Design of the theoretical framework of the application of statistical inference applied to data science

Extracurricular Activity _____

danieljiemezm.com Colombia

BLOGGER Aug 2018 - currently

Blog on Applied Statistics, Data Analysis and Machine Learning with R

Nostradamusdata.com Col-Chile

TEACHER Jun-2019- currently

Special Professor on Data Science and BI

Speaking Engagements & Conferences

- Machine Learning aplicado al mundo de la publicidad, 2020, Bogotá, Tita Media
- Interpretability Machine Learning (Labor Economics Models), 2020, Washington, BID
- Data Science and Educations, 2017, Bogotá, CTB
- Economics History: Democracy Under Threat, 2014, Bogotá, CTB
- Crime Economics in Latam: Religion and Patterns, 2013, Chile, ONU